Some things that people massively
underestimate is that happiness
and pleasure are
not the same things. Happiness, dog walks,
swim in the sea,
catching up with friends,
the finer things in life.
Pleasure, snorting coke,
partying with your mates,
going to a festival,
shagging strangers unprotected. Happiness,
pleasure.
You need to distinguish those,
because you can have a life of happiness
without
pleasure. Case in point, any of you
that have been to Asia, Indonesia, any of
those, you're like, "Whoa,
I'm surrounded by people.
This guy's only got one working flip-flop,
and he's happier than me.
This guy lives in a hammock,
and he's happier than me." Because they
have access to
happiness because they've got friends,
they've got their dog, they've got work,
they've got meaning.
They just don't have access to Gucci and
business class and Dubai brunches.
They can survive being happy without
pleasure.
But if you make the mistake
that a lot of people do,
of mistaking happiness and
pleasure, you try
and fill your happiness cup with pleasure.
You're like, "Oh,
I'm not feeling great about myself.
I'm going to go drinking.
I'm going to go do some rails of coke.
I'm not feeling great about myself.
I'm going to go out
and get some unprotected sex." And
if you try and fill your
happiness cup with pleasure,
you end up with despair.
Point I'm trying to make is this.
So many people are in the prison of
high-paying,
earning jobs where they can't see clearly
that if they were earning 200K a year
and they took a pay cut to 100K
and they went from a job they hated to a
job they
liked,
they'd be in a much better position
because they're fixated on the money.
However, when you earn less,
you still have the equal access to
happiness.
You just do not have the equal access to
pleasure.
Like I've said before,
I've had periods in my life where I've
gone completely
sober,
and that is just a decision for me to give
up some pleasure, drinking,
partying, for happiness.
And even those Saturday nights where I had
the
itch to go out when I woke up on Sunday
feeling good, it was a net benefit